Résumé Of Sarah M Rahman

House No. 35, Road No. 27, Dhanmondi, Dhaka.

Ph: 01709992043, E-mail: sarahrahman521@gmail.com



Summary

I am a communications specialist with 5+ years of experience in communications as well as in relationship management in local and multinational organisations. My areas of expertise include web and print media content development, public speaking, stakeholder management, agency supervision, CSR, diversity, branding and project management. I am a very tech-savvy professional with excellent writing skills with versatility in a range of communications solution and technologies.

Experience

Mar 2019-Present

Specialist, Sanofi Bangladesh Ltd

A global biopharmaceutical company Sanofi, previously known as sanofi-aventis is one of the topmost multinational pharmaceutical companies of Bangladesh. With a workforce of 1024, Sanofi has been working in Bangladesh for more than 62 years to improve the healthcare scenario of the country.

Responsibility:

PR and Media

- Manage the implementation of major PR and communications campaigns based on the priorities.
- Develop strong media relations develop and manage strong relationships with key stakeholders.
- Develop enterprise-wide issues management approach & lead coordination in times of crisis.
- Works closely with reputation and brand management teams to strategically align thought leadership efforts with overall business objectives.

Image Building and Branding

- Developing strategies and managing marketing campaigns across print, broadcast and online platforms to ensure that products and services meet customers' expectations and to build the credibility of brands.
- Supervising advertising, product design and other forms of marketing to maintain consistency in branding.
- Plan and drive branding strategies to create awareness of the company and the brand.

Diversity and Inclusion

- Work as diversity delegate and promote gender equality within the organization.
- Design and develop a comprehensive diversity and inclusion strategy that resulted in a more integrated and cohesive approach to and ensure a highly engaged environment.
- Created and implemented broad diversity and inclusion strategies for the organization- strategies included cultural awareness campaigns and leadership training to encourage female employees to become the future leaders.

Internal Communication and Employee Engagement

- Drive Internal Communications in line with the Group's Communications objectives.
- Plan and organize internal employee motivation/engagement programs.
- Work with HR and other Business Units to develop and deploy its employee communication strategy to accelerate growth.

Digital Communications

- Contribute to editorial contents of the internet site, in partnership with the IT Department.
- Provide editorial support for the affiliate intranet site to the IT Department.
- Work with the IT Department to implement technological advances in intranet portal.

CSR

- Identify and drive projects as per the Group's humanitarian sponsorship strategy and guidelines.
- Inform and involve employees in local humanitarian sponsorship initiatives.
- Develop and maintain trust-based relationships with humanitarian organizations and NGO.

Mar 2017- Feb 2019	Senior Communications Executive, Sanofi Bangladesh Ltd
Oct 2015- Feb 2017	Communications Executive, Sanofi Bangladesh Ltd
Jan 2015-	Sales Executive, Shanta Holdings
Sep 2015	Real Estate Developer
Jun 2014-	Trainee - Key Account Management, LM Ericsson Bangladesh
Dec 2014	LM Ericsson Bangladesh Limited is one of the topmost telecommunication service providers of the world and has been operating in Bangladesh since 1996

Education

Ongoing	University of Dhaka Master of Business Administration (MBA), Marketing
2014	North South University Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA), Marketing & Human Resources Management
2008	A-Level
2006	O-Level

Skills

• Corporate Communications • Product Positioning and Branding • Digital Web and Print Content Development • Intranet Portal Management • New Product Launch • Adobe Photoshop, Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel etc.

Key Achievement/Projects

- Develop growth driving project in 2018 to increase number of sales achievers which increased achievers for Q1 and Q2 from 47% to 59%.
- 'Departmental Fair' a fair where departments showcased their achievement through different visual elements.
 This was organized on zonal VP visiting Bangladesh and was highly appreciated by internal and zonal management.
- Conceptualized and executed the first Heritage Branding Campaign of Sanofi to uphold its brand legacy amongst its key stakeholders.
- Sanofi Employee of the Month: August 2016, September 2016, March 2017,

References

Farhana Tofail

Head of Communications

Sanofi Bangladesh Ltd, Mobile: 01709992010

Al Batuni Sayed Ahmed

Vice President Sales and Marketing

LM Ericsson Bangladesh, Mobile: 01611224466